ARMANDO GONZALEZ

Atlanta, GA • U.S. Citizen armandogonz14@gatech.edu • 201-290-4979

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Armando Gonzalez is a passionate, personable team player, with early experience in software development and an intense interest for developing products centered on an intuitive, clear, and capable user experience. In his free time, he enjoys free writing and making art of many forms – from narrative poetry, to pixel drawings and small video games.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, College of Computing Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Atlanta, Georgia

May 2020

- Concentration in *Media and People*
- Seeking a certificate in *Entrepreneurship*

SKILLS

Technical: Proficiency in Java, Golang, Python, Elasticsearch, AWS;

Familiarity with C, Android Development, AngularJS, Sql, Shell Scripting

Application: Proficiency in Object Oriented Programming, Restful Web Services, Service Development;

Familiarity with Aspect Oriented Programming, Application Development, Game Development

Leadership: Running and Planning Events, Organization and Leadership of Groups, Project Management

Communication: Public Speaking (Presentational, Interpersonal, and Written), Group Mediation and Problem Solving

PROJECTS

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

VIP Research Program

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018

- Developed a database-backed, live map with JS utilized by managers of Georgia Tech's bus system
- Collected data on bus system behavior using an Android application and Estimote beacons

Android Application Development

Spring 2017

- Developed an application in class that allows users to submit and view water reports in the area
- Application backed by a live database and uses a live updated Google map

Gameboy Advance Game Development

Spring 2018

- Created a game for the Gameboy Advance called *Bit-a-Fish*
- Wrote the entirety of the game code in C
- Created original art for the game's sprites

MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

Wrote a script to check the health of various app deployments in real time	Summer 2016
Implemented a powerful, free-form, and text-based search engine for a web-based application	Summer 2016
Performed an extensive backfill of media data using Amazon Web Services	Summer 2017

PATIENTCO

Rebuilt a search engine to improve its speed, accuracy, and flexibility when searching patient data	Fall 2017
Wrote an internal tool/service that used OCR to read images and searched for associated information	Summer 2018

EXPERIENCE

MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL, ADVANCED MEDIA

New York, New York

Summer 2016

- Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Development Team
 Shortly graduated from small projects to full-stack applications
- Actively participated on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Projects required exposure to all major touch points of MLBAM's technical ecosystem
- Delivered several formal demos and presentations to other interns and members of the Engineering Department

Software Engineering Intern, Multimedia Development Team

Summer 2017

- Worked as an independent, full-stack engineer in a fast-paced environment
- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Scrum)
- Participated in a department-wide Hackathon that exposed me to other teams within Engineering

PATIENTCO Atlanta, Georgia Fall 2017

Software Engineering Coop, Platform Team

- Individually developed a net-new service and designed a search cluster using Elasticsearch and Golang
- Developed production level software on a team practicing Agile Software Development (Kanban)
- Participated in a career fair and other follow-up recruiting efforts on behalf of the company
- Delivered a formal demo and presentation to other members of the Engineering Department and C.S.O.

Lead Software Engineering Coop, Platform Team

Summer 2018

- Performed as lead developer on another net-new service with cross-departmental stakeholders
- Managed an internal project using Agile Software (Kanban) Methods and taught these methods to others
- Delivered several formal demos and presentation to other members of the Engineering Department, and Customer Support

LEADERSHIP

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Georgia Tech Spirit Program, Spirit Leader

Atlanta, Georgia Fall 2017 - Present

- Represents Georgia Tech on local, state, and national level as an ambassador and symbol for Georgia Tech
- Maintain strict fitness and diet regimen, training triweekly at 5:30am while balancing school and extracurriculars
- Commit an average of 10 hours per week towards attending on and off campus events with high energy and enthusiasm

New Student and Sophomore Programs, Orientation Director of Staff Development

Fall 2017 – Present

- Led a staff of 40 through weekly trainings focused on group mediation and leadership
- Attended the Southern Regional Orientation Workshop to learn more about leadership and group management
- Helped plan a three-day, extended orientation camp to help transition incoming Georgia Tech students

New Student and Sophomore Programs, Orientation Leader

Spring 2016 – Fall 2017

- Co-led a small group of students as a part of an extended orientation program
- Joined a staff of 30+ students focused on community building and transitioning into life at Georgia Tech